Easy, little guy.
What's he doing?
You wanna live?
I'm just…
I wanna die in here.
Yeah?
I get it.
Thank you for this meal.
LIFE IN THE WOODS
BY HENRY DAVID THOREAU
It's so beautiful.
Yes.
Dad…
Let's say there really was a God.
What would you ask for?
Aah…
Hmm…
That there would be
more mountains for us to climb!
Where no human being has ever been.
Please, dear God!
You're crazy.
Mountains like that don't exist
in the world today, Yuzuha.
Your turn, now.
I want this moment to last forever!
A mountaintop…
is where I…
A mountaintop is
where I can really be myself.
Dad, you are the only one
who makes me believe
that I have a place in this world.
I wanna live this moment forever.
You'd get bored.
That's his daughter!
- There she is!
- Ms. Usagi! Ms. Usagi!
- I just wanna ask you…
- Did he actually climb Mount Everest?
Is it true that your father didn't
actually make the climb
that he said he did?
Please… Ms. Usagi, Ms. Usagi, over here!
Please comment, please!
Welcome home.
Dad.
Don't you worry.
I don't know who's spreading these lies,
but I've always told you the truth.
Where are you going?
To the mountain.
Dad, wait.
The mountain…
is where I can really be myself.
STAGED?
SOLO NO-OXYGEN MOUNTAIN CLIMBING
SUSPECTED TO BE STAGED
HE USED AN OXYGEN SUPPLEMENT
IT WAS AN IMPOSSIBLE CHALLENGE
IN THE FIRST PLACE
DID USAGI STAGE THE ENTIRE EVENT?
550-STRONG SEARCH PARTY
LOOK FOR MISSING CLIMBER
NO CLUES ON HIS WHEREABOUTS
WORLD-FAMOUS MOUNTAINEER MISSING
DID SHIGENORI USAGI
COMMIT SUICIDE
DUE TO SUSPICIONS
ON STAGED MOUNTAIN CLIMBING?
SUICIDE
Thank you for the meal.
Why did you save me?
Your body says, "I want to live."
My body?
Might say it wants to live…
But I don't deserve to live anymore.
They're all dead.
And I'm the only one still alive.
They all had to die so I could survive.
I might as well have been the one
who killed them all.
I killed them all.
I don't deserve to live.
Not after I let them all die.
I have to die.
I have to die!
I have to die to be with them.
I need to die!
I need to make it up to all of them!
I need to make amends
for everything I've done!
Why?
I…
I'm hungry.
I understand.
There was a time I wanted to die too.
Just like you do.
I was just laying on the ground.
And I started feeling hungry.
I know one day, I will die.
And it could be
when we're playing the game tomorrow
or when my visa expires.
But for now, I made that food.
So eat it while you're still alive.
Get ready.
You've got a game to play.
Are you planning to die
by having your visa expire?
That time you screamed at all of us.
During the tag game…
You risked your life
trying to save everyone.
- Everyone!
- Hey!
He's up here! Over here,
he's on the second level!
Tell us where he is if you see him!
And let's all look for the symbol!
I didn't wanna die then.
And I didn't want anyone else too, either.
I know what you're saying.
And I don't want you to die now.
If you hadn't screamed back there,
I'd be dead now.
Let me repay you.
THIS WAY TO THE GAME ARENA
THE GAME ARENA IS UP AHEAD
1 PER PERSON
FACE RECOGNITION IN PROGRESS
PLEASE WAIT FOR A MOMENT
You're not newbies.
And who are you?
We're the guys
who cleared four games together.
We met at the first game
and now we work together as a team.
But we might need more
if we're gonna clear this one.
And your leg? Are you hurt?
Ah… I tweaked it a bit.
In the game?
Yeah.
Okay, the game's starting.
Registration is now closed.
The game is about to commence.
Difficulty, Four of Clubs.
There are a total of five participants.
Game, "Distance".
"Distance"?
Rule. Endure the trial
while striving for the goal
within the time limit.
Clear condition.
Safely attain the goal.
What is this?
The game will now commence.
120 minutes remaining.
Does this mean we have to run?
What do you think, Seizan?
"Distance"?
Zero.
We have to run? On the highway?
Uh, run?
Takuma. Just relax.
Sit down, sit down.
I think these old buses
from the '70s all have V8 engines.
Let's hope it starts.
Come on, baby!
Shit! It's out of gas.
Looks like we have to run.
Go on. Leave me here.
- Takuma!
- Listen to me.
I don't plan to just sit on my ass here,
roll over, and die.
I'm gonna try to find a way to survive.
But you gotta go.
- We're not leaving you behind!
- Yamane!
You gotta survive, so go now!
You wanna see your wife again, right?
And what about that baby she's carrying?
What the hell are they supposed to do
without you?
Don't worry about me. I got this.
Yamane.
Let's go.
Go on.
Now.
You can do this.
Let's go.
He made the right choice.
110 minutes remaining.
Arisu.
Live for us.
Thank you.
Distance, 1,000.
90 minutes remaining.
To reach the goal,
how much further do we have to run?
Distance, 5,000.
Hey.
What's that?
REPLENISHMENT STATION
We made it.
Wait.
- Hang on a sec.
- Eh?
You're waiting for us to drink it,
aren't you?
No, we're not.
Drink this.
Thank you.
That was great.
Are you sure?
Uh-huh.
Distance, 6,000.
Man, it's dark in here.
Shit, this isn't Clubs.
It's gotta be a game of Spades.
Something's over there.
I don't see anything.
Yeah. Right there.
Run!
Oh my god, oh my god. Help me!
Help!
No! Get off!
Seizan!
- Let's go!
- Come on!
Get off!
Seizan! Seizan!
- I can't run anymore.
- Come on!
I'm done.
I can't.
I'd only been with them…
for about a week, but…
it's like I knew them both…
for my entire life.
You gotta live.
So you can tell your wife about them.
You're right.
Distance, 8,000.
What are you doing?
A motorcycle.
Royal Enfield.
You know bikes?
Diesel engines like that are pretty rare.
But old stuff like this still works
since none of it has any IC chips.
Hang on.
Electronics.
All electrical circuits
have been destroyed.
So?
Analog stuff
with no electrical circuitry still works.
All motorcycles and all the cars
still work.
Like this bike, or that bus back there!
Damn it, no battery.
This bike, you said it's got
an old diesel engine, right?
Uh-huh.
So it doesn't run on regular gas,
but diesel.
- So does the bus, nice!
- Uh-huh.
Wait, so…
You want to carry that bike
all the way back with you?
If we get this fuel back there,
we can use the bus and save Takuma.
You wanna save Takuma?
- Uh-huh.
- But if we go back,
then the game can't be cleared!
Yes it can. There's still enough time.
But just in case, you two keep going.
If I can start that bus,
I'll catch up real fast.
No more surviving
by letting other people die.
I'm done with it.
Distance, 7,000.
Distance, 10,000.
Distance, 6,000.
Distance, 12,000.
Distance, 4,000.
What?
That's the goal.
All right, let's wait for them.
Distance, 1,000.
15 minutes remaining.
Hey!
ENTRY PROHIBITED
Your wife?
This autumn, we're expecting a baby.
I'm sure
they're waiting for you somewhere.
Somewhere…
they're waiting.
Everyone's waiting.
They're all out there somewhere.
So you have to stay alive to see them.
Five minutes remaining.
Doesn't look like they made it.
What the hell was that?
What is that?
Water?
I can't run anymore!
Yes, you can! Don't look back!
Ah!
Usagi!
Arisu!
Arisu.
Oh, it hurts.
Are you all right?
Thank you. Thanks.
Goal.
So this whole time…
I was at the goal?
It was right there for us to see.
The bus was the goal from the very start.
Then what were all those numbers about?
The distance to the goal.
We were safe at zero.
Game cleared.
Congratulations.
I got you.
Hey, wait! Where are you going?
I, uh…
I have no idea.
But I hope that…
we'll meet again.
The Beach?
Maybe the people
who disappeared are there.
Could it be
some kind of evacuation shelter?
Yeah, maybe.
But there's an answer out there.
And I wanna remember Karube's words.
I'm gonna do it for everyone.
I'm gonna find the mastermind
of this sick game.
And get this world back to the way it was.
I swear it.
But to do that,
I have to head to the Beach.
You really don't know how to ride a bike?
I never learned how.
That's pretty hard to believe.
But this feels nice.